## TSUNGAI M. CHIMBWANDA

# JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER ENERGISED BY FINTECH AND CONTRIBUTING TO THE EMPOWERMENT OF DISADVANTAGED PEOPLE

(403).467.9794 | TSUNGAICHI@GMAIL.COM | CALGARY, TREATY 7
IN IN/TSUNGAICHIMBWANDA | TSUNGIC.GITHUB.IO/TSUNGAI

### PERSONAL PROFILE

2+ years of professional bookkeeping, economic driven university projects and provincially awarded social entrepreneurship I have become a full stack developer to pursue financial technology. I have 6+ years of experience across client-facing sales, training, and service roles, with proven results in top-grossing sales of a medium-sized business and caring for vulnerable individuals in the public sector. My knack for nurturing client relationships has translated into five-figure revenues leading to promotion. I get a genuine kick out of presenting, training, and facilitating. Always eager to execute new business opportunities, I will be continuing my education and career in Information Technology. Looking forward, I hope to combine my analytical and creative mind to assist product development in Financial Technology and provide innovative solutions for customers.

Front End Programming | Back End Programming | Bookkeeping | Data Entry | Sales | Social Venture

### **EDUCATION**

## FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPEMENT 09.2020- 03.2021

Innotech College, Calgary

## BACHELOR OF ARTS: MAJOR ECONOMICS 2015-2018

University of Calgary (Completed 2 years)

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

## CO-FOUNDER | Home in a Bag 2019

Awarded Top 10 Most exportable startups by Startup Canada for social entrepreneurship and testing of minimal viable product by Samaritan's Purse.

## PRINCIPAL DANCER D Rhythm Soul Dance 2018-2020

Principal dancer and assistant coach, choreographing and training for Miss Teen Caribbean in St. Kitss 2019. Working with teen girls and meeting with Caribbean Government officials.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS & LANGUAGES

HTML | CSS| JAVASCRIPT | SASS | VUE.JS SQL | PHP | PYTHON | FLASK | API | GIT BASH | OOP

ENGLISH: NATIVE | SHONA: NOVICE

## CORE STRENGTHS

### **PROBLEM SOLVING & ORGANIZATION**

"Tsungai has excellent communication skills. In addition she is extremely organized, reliable and computer literate. Tsungai can work independently and is able to follow through to ensure that the job gets done. She is flexible and willing to work on any project assigned to her. I was continually impressed by the knowledge she brought to the table and her dedication." -Roukayatou Mahamadou (Alberta Justice, prior supervisor)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

### RECORDS MANAGEMENT & Front Desk Alberta Justice Minister: Office of Public Guardian and Trustee 03.2020 - 09.2020

- Documentation: Ensure clear and concise record keeping of all M-Z (1000+) clients across Calgary and surrounding areas files are available as necessary and in the provincial data base
- Case management: Adapted to meet individual client needs by displaying highest level of professionalism and sensitivity for grieving family member, vulnerable clients and client intervention
- Improved efficiency of filing systems which resulted in decreased time spend by co-workers search for files and distrusted documents to all 7 departments to optimize supervisors daily case load

## HEAD BARTENDER (promotion) Mount Royal University | 03.2018 - 12.2020

- **Lead** a team of 14 leading to top 2 highest gross net days in since open during private events of 600+ patrons
- Trained 3 colleagues providing one to one training sessions, conducting quality control checks, opening and closing POS systems leading to promotion
- **Allocated** and replenished inventory to 5 locations across campus by conducting thorough analysis of current selling patterns, sell-throughs, inventory levels, and growth forecasting

## BOOKKEEPER & Front Desk Grant Production Testing | 10.2017 - 05.2018

- Worked with vice president of finance to coordinate daily, biweekly and monthly account payables, receivables, invoicing and data entry using Excel, reporting 3 discrepancies
- Assisted human resources manager with Answering general phone and email inquiries, copying, filing and faxing Contacted 6 companies on followups of payments

#### **BOOKKEEPER**

## MC Professional Accountant | 06.2017- 09.2017 (temporary )

- Prepared and completed sets of financial statement for accounts payable and account receivable utilizing QuickBooks averaging 300+ daily cash receipts, bank reconciliation, disbursement chargebacks and billing entries
- Identified, fixed & reported issues found during monthly and quarterly personal profit and loss statements